What's up, everyone? Are you ready to become an English detective?
みんな、こんにちは！英語の探偵になる準備はできた？
Today, we're going to crack a secret code.
今日は秘密のコードを解読するよ。
A special phrase that answers the biggest, most important question of all, why?
それは、すべての重要な質問、なぜ？に答える特別なフレーズ。
Let's get into it. You know, think about it for a second.
さあ、始めよう。少し考えてみて。
Every day, we see people doing all sorts of things.
毎日、いろんなことをしている人を見かけるよね。
They're running, they're studying, they're going places.
走ったり、勉強したり、出かけたり。
But just knowing what they're doing, well, that's only half the story.
でも、彼らが何をしているか知るだけでは、話の半分に過ぎない。
The real story, the super interesting part, is the reason behind it all.
本当の話、面白い部分は、その理由なんだ。
So today we're gonna uncover that why, ready? Okay, check this out.
今日はその「なぜ」を明らかにするよ。準備はいい？さあ、見てみよう。
She went to the station. I mean, it's a sentence, it works,
彼女は駅に行った。文としては成立しているけど、
but it kind of leaves you hanging, right?
なんだか物足りないよね？
It makes you go, hmm, but why? Why'd she go there?
「でも、なぜ？彼女はなぜそこに行ったの？」
Was she catching a train to Tokyo? Meeting up with a friend?
東京行きの電車に乗るため？友達と会うため？
We need the details. Well, you are in luck
詳細が必要だね。今日は運がいいよ。
because today we are unlocking the magic words.
今日は魔法の言葉を解き明かすから。
This is the secret code that answers our why question
これが私たちの「なぜ」に答える秘密のコード。
like every single time. It's super simple, it's really powerful,
とてもシンプルで、力強いものなんだ。
and you're about to become a master at using it. Whoa, okay.
これを使いこなすマスターになれるよ。さあ、行こう。
Don't let this big fancy grammar name scare you off.
この難しい文法用語に驚かないで。
Adverbial to infinitive. All that is is just an expert way of saying
「不定詞の副詞的用法」って言うけど、
we use to plus a verb to explain why we do something.
要するに、何かをする理由を説明するために「to + 動詞」を使うってこと。
Just think of it like this.
こう考えてみて。
It's the phrase that means in order to do something.
何かをするために、という意味のフレーズなんだ。
That's it, it's our key. So let's start with a really basic action.
それが私たちの鍵。では、基本的な行動から始めよう。
You hear this one all the time, right?
これ、よく聞くよね？
Your teachers say it, your parents say it, you must work hard.
先生も言うし、親も言う、「一生懸命働きなさい」。
And yeah, it's great advice for sure. But again, why?
確かに素晴らしいアドバイスだけど、また「なぜ？」がある。
What's the point? What's the goal?
目的は何？目標は？
And boom, there it is, to pass the exam.
そして、そこにあるのが「試験に合格するため」。
That's our secret code right there in action.
これが私たちの秘密のコードだ。
That little phrase, to pass, tells us the entire reason,
「合格するため」というフレーズが、全ての理由を教えてくれる。
the whole purpose for working hard. So here's the main point.
一生懸命働く目的がわかるね。だから、ポイントはこれ。
Two plus verb is the direct answer to the question, why?
「to + 動詞」は「なぜ？」の直接的な答えなんだ。
And once you know what to look for,
何を探せばいいか分かれば、
you start seeing this code everywhere. Let's solve these missions.
このコードがどこにでもあることに気づくよ。さあ、ミッションを解決しよう。
I got up early, but why? To catch the first train.
早起きしたけど、なぜ？初電に乗るため。
And what about our original mystery? She went to the station. Why?
元の謎はどう？彼女は駅に行った。なぜ？
To meet her parents. Mission solved. Or how about this one?
両親に会うため。ミッション完了。次はこれ。
He practices every day to join the basketball team.
彼は毎日練習して、バスケットボールチームに入るため。
That's a great goal. And my personal favorite,
素晴らしい目標だね。そして私のお気に入りは、
I saved my money to buy tickets for the Taylor Swift concert.
「テイラー・スウィフトのコンサートのチケットを買うためにお金を貯めた」。
I mean, yes, the Eris tour. Absolutely worth it.
そう、エリスツアー。絶対に価値があるよ。
See how that little why makes every sentence so much more interesting?
この「なぜ」があることで、すべての文がもっと面白くなるよね？
Okay, you have officially learned the secret code.
さて、あなたは正式に秘密のコードを学んだ。
So level one is complete. Now it's time for level two,
レベル1は完了。次はレベル2、
becoming a true master of style. So the next question is,
本物のスタイルのマスターになること。次の質問は、
where exactly can we put this awesome phrase in a sentence?
この素晴らしいフレーズを文のどこに入れられるか？
So turns out you've got options, which is cool.
実は選択肢があるんだ、いいね。
You can do what we've been doing and put the main action first
これまでのように、主な行動を最初に持ってきて、
and then the purpose at the end.
目的を最後に置くこともできる。
You must work hard to pass the exam, simple.
「試験に合格するために、一生懸命働かなければならない」、シンプルだね。
But if you wanna sound a little more dramatic,
でも、もっとドラマチックに聞こえたいなら、
you can put the purpose first. To pass the exam, you must work hard.
目的を最初に持ってくることもできる。「試験に合格するために、一生懸命働かなければならない」。
The meaning is exactly the same, but look really closely.
意味は全く同じだけど、よく見てみて。
When you put the why at the beginning,
「なぜ」を最初に持ってくると、
you have to add that super important little comma right there.
その重要な小さなコンマを追加しなければならない。
Here are a couple more great examples of putting that purpose first.
目的を最初に持ってくる素晴らしい例をいくつか紹介するよ。
To save money, we eat at home.
「お金を節約するために、私たちは家で食べる」。
The goal is super clear from the very beginning
目的が最初から明確だね。
or to help his parents, he cleans the house every day.
「両親を助けるために、彼は毎日家を掃除する」。
Putting that reason upfront is a really strong
その理由を最初に伝えるのは、
and clear way to communicate what you mean.
意味を明確に伝える強い方法です。
All right team, you've learned the code,
さあ、チーム、コードを学び、
you've learned the different styles.
さまざまなスタイルを学びました。
I think it's time to put those skills to the test. It's quiz time.
そろそろそのスキルを試す時です。クイズの時間です。
Let's see if you can unscramble these sentences and find the why.
これらの文を並べ替えて、理由を見つけてみてください。
You ready? Here is your first mission. The words are all jumbled up.
準備はいいですか？最初のミッションです。言葉が混ざっています。
Your job is to figure out the action, figure out the purpose,
あなたの仕事は、行動を見つけ、目的を考え、
and put them together in the right order. I'll give you a second.
それらを正しい順序で組み合わせることです。少し時間をあげます。
Go for it. And the answer is, they went to the park to play baseball.
さあ、どうぞ。そして答えは、彼らは公園に野球をしに行ったです。
The action, they went to the park. the reason why to play baseball.
行動は、公園に行ったこと。理由は、野球をするためです。
Did you get it right? Awesome work. All right, you are on a roll.
正解でしたか？素晴らしい仕事です。調子がいいですね。
Let's keep that energy going. Here's round two.
その勢いを保ちましょう。次はラウンド2です。
We've got studied, French, Go, and France. So what's the story here?
「勉強した」「フランス語」「行く」「フランス」。さて、ここでのストーリーは？
Get unscrambling. Yes, he studied French to go to France.
並べ替えてみてください。はい、彼はフランスに行くためにフランス語を勉強しました。
Fantastic. The action is studying French.
素晴らしい。行動はフランス語を勉強することです。
And the purpose, the dream is to go to France.
目的は、フランスに行くことです。
He probably wants to see the Eiffel Tower. Now that is an awesome why.
彼はおそらくエッフェル塔を見たいのでしょう。それが素晴らしい理由です。
Okay, last challenge for you and I want you to pay close attention.
さて、最後の挑戦です。注意深く見てください。
This one gives you a massive clue. The very first word is two.
これには大きなヒントがあります。最初の言葉は「to」です。
What does that tell you about how the sentence is gonna be built?
それは文がどう構築されるかを示していますか？
You got this. And the correct answer is
あなたならできます。そして正解は、
to buy a new bike, she saved money. Nailed it.
「新しい自転車を買うために、彼女はお金を貯めた」です。完璧です。
You saw that two at the beginning
最初の「to」を見て、
and you knew the purpose was gonna come first,
目的が最初に来ると分かりましたね。
followed by that super important comma. You guys are officially pros.
その後に重要なコンマが続きます。皆さんはプロです。
Incredible job on that quiz. Seriously.
クイズで素晴らしい仕事をしました。本当に。
So let's wrap this up with a quick summary
では、簡単なまとめで締めくくり、
and then I'm gonna share one final expert level tip
最後に役立つ専門的なヒントをお伝えします。
that will help you avoid a really common mix up.
これを知れば、二度と間違えません。
Okay, I want you to look really closely at this slide
さて、このスライドをよく見てください。
because this can be a little tricky sometimes.
これが時々少し難しいことがあります。
Both of these sentences start with to study English
両方の文は「英語を勉強する」で始まりますが、
but in the first one to study English is very important.
最初の文では「英語を勉強する」が非常に重要です。
We're talking about the act of studying. It's the what. It's a thing.
勉強する行為について話しています。それが「何」です。
But in our second sentence, to study English, he went to Australia, we're talking about
しかし、二つ目の文「英語を勉強するために、彼はオーストラリアに行った」では、
our secret code for why. And that little comma is the big visual clue.
理由について話しています。そして、その小さなコンマが大きな視覚的手がかりです。
It's like a secret signal that tells you, hey, this is the reason for the action.
それは、行動の理由を示す秘密の信号のようなものです。
That's a pro tip right there. So let's put it all together.
これがプロのヒントです。では、すべてをまとめましょう。
Here is your brand new superpower in four easy steps, your why power up.
これがあなたの新しいスーパーパワーです。4つの簡単なステップで、あなたの「なぜ」を強化します。
Step one, find the action. What's happening?
ステップ1、行動を見つける。何が起こっているのか？
Step two, ask yourself why.
ステップ2、自分に「なぜ」と問いかける。
Step three, use the secret code 2 plus verb to give the reason.
ステップ3、理由を示すために秘密のコード「to + 動詞」を使う。
And step four, choose your style.
ステップ4、スタイルを選ぶ。
Put the code at the end or at the start with a comma.
コードを文の最後か最初にコンマと共に置きます。
That's the whole thing.
これが全てです。
This last example really brings our whole mission together.
この最後の例は、私たちのミッションをまとめます。
We're looking at a simple sentence again.
再びシンプルな文を見ています。
She studied hard to pass the exam.
彼女は試験に合格するために一生懸命勉強しました。
But now, you don't just see a bunch of words, do you? You see a story.
しかし今、ただの言葉の集まりではなく、物語が見えます。
You see an action and you see a clear purpose.
行動と明確な目的が見えます。
You have officially cracked the code.
あなたは公式にコードを解読しました。
So remember, this isn't just about grammar.
これは文法だけの話ではありません。
This is about your life and your goals.
これはあなたの人生と目標についてです。
So I'm going to leave you with this question. What's your why?
では、この質問を残します。あなたの「なぜ」は何ですか？
What's the purpose behind what you're doing?
あなたがしていることの目的は何ですか？
Maybe it's to join the soccer team, or to travel to America, or just to learn something
サッカーチームに参加するためか、アメリカに旅行するためか、新しいことを学ぶためかもしれません。
new.
どんな目標でも、
Whatever your goal is, now you know exactly how to say it in English.
今や英語でそれをどう言うかが分かりました。
Thanks for cracking the code with me today.
今日は一緒にコードを解読してくれてありがとう。